大家好！我是你们的好兄弟 Jonathan Burton
Hey guys it's me it's your best friend
来自Carbon Animations
it's Jonathan Burton Carbon animations
我收到了很多观众对于动画教学的问题
and I get a lot of questions about tutorial videos
今天我将教你们用最简单的办法做动画
and today I'm gonna give you the simplest way to animate
可能这么说并不准确，但这确实是一种很好的练习
well it's not really, but it's a good exercise,
有助于你理解动画制作
and it helps you understand animation
所谓动画
if you know what animation is,
它研究运动
it is the study of motion.
它是生命的幻象(The illusion of life也是一本动画教程书籍的名字)
It is the illusion of life,
有些逐帧作画的感觉
and it is framed by frame work kinda.
但也不是所有的动画都需要逐帧来画
I mean, it doesn't always have to be frame by frame.
今天我们将要学习绘画运动效果
But today we're going to study the motion
这将有助于理解动画制作过程，以及物体如何在画布空间中移动
and it's gonna help to understand how to animate and how things move in the space on the canvas.
我认为这很有用
I think it's really helpful.
这就是"点动画"
It's called Dot animation.
科班学习的第一课通常会让你画一个球
So in school, usually they make you animate a ball as the first thing.
但我们只画一个点
but we're going to do a dot.
画点更简单，因为一个球体有外形样式，而点就很简单
It's even simpler because a ball it has it's got form *or a dot is just a dot.
接下来要画出一个点以及我们想让它执行的动作
so we're going to animate a dot and a motion that we want.
目标是让一个角色助跑并跳过已经画好的小沟
And so we want a character to run and jump across this this little pit here that I've already drawn,
想要让角色动作看起来更完美
and so that character we want the motion to look good *though,
可以先用画点的方式来练习
so we're going to practice with a dot,
这个点就代表着人物
as if the dot is running and jumping,
在这里先画个点
so the dot is going to be over here,
点的位置大概就是人物胸部的位置
and it's gonna represent the kind of the, I guess the chest of the character.
这样点就画好了 我要把笔的压感关了
OK, so there's the dots, actually I'm going to remove my pressure sensitivity,
这样点的大小就不会变
so the dot doesn't change really,
我们要让这个点跳过小沟
there's the dots and we're going to make the dot run and jump across this,
这个过程就是角色奔跑跳跃的样板
and that's going to give us our template for our motion of a character running and jumping.
打开绘图纸外观模式(Alt+Shift+O),按F7创建新的帧
Alright we're gonna have onion skin turned on press F7 to form new frame.
绘图纸模式可以同时显示先前帧和之后的帧
and because the onion skin, we're going to see our previous frame and the next frame.
目前我们还没画下一帧
We have no next frame,
但我们现在已经可以看到前一帧了
but we're gonna see our previous frame here,
小点会缓慢提速
and so the dot is gonna start to slowly build up some speed,
我还会让它略微弹跳一下
and I'm even going to bounce it up and down a bit
因为人的奔跑动作就是这样的
Because that's how people run.
弹跳的幅度不需要太大
I'm going to bounce up and down just a little bit.
继续画
More.
小点逐步地运动到另一边
And we're going to start to gradually drag this across.
点之间的间距会越来越远
Gradually move further and further apart with the dots,
因为它运动得越来越快
because that means the character is getting faster and faster,
确保每次画点的时候略微增加间距
so we gotta make sure we're moving a little bit further apart each time we do a dots.
这里角色略微停顿准备跳跃
and the character is going to kind of *windup for a jump off it,
就要画得离地面近一些
so I'm going to make them stay closer to the ground.
画出一点点减速的效果
And even even kind of.
因为角色要做起跳前的准备动作
Slow down a little bit because you wind up for that jump.
接下去就是跳跃动作
So he's going to jump.
第一帧要远一些
the first frame is going to be a little bit further.
之后角色离地
And then, as you jump in the air,
在横向和纵向都会减速
you start to slow down both in height and in distance.
因为速度变慢
because the speed is starting to wear off.
现在它已经跳过了小沟
it looks like he's going to completely clear this gap here.
接下来就是落地
And again, the landing.
因为落地需要一些调整的时间
because he's landing is going to be a bit of recovery time.
搞定了
that's it OK?
奔跑跳跃
So run jump.
是不是有内味了？
It looks like it, okay?
有点像了
Looks like it.
你也可以简化一下
You can make it simpler,
你也可以省略弹跳的过程，其他照做就行
you don't have to add the bouncing in just if you don't have the bouncing and you just do the exact same thing,
只要确保每次的间距增加就行
you just make sure you're doing it a little bit further apart each time.
再画一次没有弹跳的过程
So again, this is it. Without a bouncing.
增加一点点间距
And you just do it a little bit further apart.
直到你觉得到达最大速度时
Until you feel like, okay, that's Max speed okay yeah,
这就是最大速度下的间距
it's going to be that far apart is Max speed.
接下来还是同样的步骤，画跳跃动作
And you do the exact same thing and then you can do the jump.
同样的方法
that's again similar.
正视错误，及时改正
And don't be afraid to cancel it. Dots deleted.
这样就画好了
there you go And this will be.
你可以做出同样的效果
So you can do the exact same thing.
这就是跳过小沟的一个很好的动作示例
so that is too... very, very fine motions of running and jumping over a pit,
现在你就可以照着我的原版来试着做了
and now you can follow the dots when you want to only use my original one,
按点的轨迹来画
you can follow that dots.
接下来我将帮助你做出完整的动画
*And I'll help(hope?) you to actually do it.
再看一个更短更简单的例子
Let's see the other one because it's shorter and also its simpler
我们希望例子尽可能简单
and we want to keep things as simple as possible.
因此我把点变成了小红圈
So I made the dot into a red the little circle.
只需要按一下这个按键(将所有图层显示为轮廓)
By hitting this color code button.
接下来要把它变成枪兵
And then we'll make it into a marine
枪兵是星际2中画的最快的单位了
marine is the quickest thing to draw in Starcraft.
和之前一样，只画一个角色
So again. We'll just uses a character,
然后就是相同的运动轨迹
and then he starts to run and again we can use the exact same motion.
跑步循环则有些不同
and run cycles are a little bit different,
跑步循环有个另外的教程
There is a lesson on their own.
今天我们不涉及跑步循环的教程
And we're not going to be run cycle today,
只是展示这个运动轨迹可以用作参考
but just to show that you can use that motion as a guide.
运动轨迹非常有用
And that it does work
当需要事先测试运动效果时，这是一种不错的方式。
and it's a good little template you can give yourself, you want to test out the motion first and that it's a decent way to do it.
它跑得越来越快
He's now getting faster,
红圈要在头的中间位置
and again it's going to be like in the middle of his head here.
我不会花太多时间在角色细节上
And I'm not going to spend too much time on the actual character.
你可以用符号来表示奔跑动画
You can use a symbol for run animation.
其实我应该提前准备一个跑步动画，这样效果会好得多
Actually I should have probably prepared one that would have been a lot nicer.
你明白我的意思
Yes, you get the idea.
如果你有已经做好的跑步动画
If you have a run animation already set,
只需要让它跟着运动点就可以了
Then you just make it follow the dots and you're good to go.
如果没有的话，也可以用符号代替
But if not, you could make a run animation symbol.
还是让符号跟随运动点
And then make it follow the dot as well.
现在枪兵要准备跳过去
Now he's going to start to wind up for his jump,
所以需要下蹲一些
so he's going to go a little lower. Lower again,
我有时候会很敷衍地做这部分动画
Sometimes I do this kind of animation episode where it's just very, very sloppy
还挺管用，因为我们每周都有一堆工作要做
and you know it works because we have bunch of cartoons *to do every week,
当工作量远超你的能力时，就可以用这种办法来应付更多事情
*but also it's far away if things are far away than you can, you can get away with a lot more things.
效果还可以
*It doesn't look as nearly as bad
接着画下去
here we are to do.
跳起来
Jumping.
照着模板做就行
Again, just following your template.
画出空中动作
Into the air.
画出四肢
His limbs,
四肢要略微落后于整体的运动方向
*always dragging behind a bits of what he's doing.
压扁一些
Squish that down.
注意身体的朝向，因为身体的指向就是运动的方向
*where his bodies going because his body is leading the way.
必须保证红点在角色头部位置
Got to make sure the red dot is where his ahead is.
落地
and he lands.
像这样低头
His head down like this.
再低一些
It goes down a little bit more.
四肢也朝下
And now his limbs come down too,
开始调整动作
and I started to recover
缩小帧的范围，因为不需要用到之前的帧做参考了
and take away some onion skin frames because I don't need them
开始站起来
he starts to recover a bit.
四肢朝下，同时抬头
And his limbs are down and he looks up.
这部分内容
In this part, I mean I don't like, I mean,
如果你是个新手，我不要求你把这部分全画出来
if you're new at animation I don't expect you just animate completely this part here.
你需要做的是画出角色的某一部分，比如主体部分
What you want to do is animates one one piece of the character like the body, the main body,
之后才增加细节
and then the details after.
就是这种效果
*But this is how it looks.
它始终跟随着这些点移动
And it follows the exact same animations as the dots.
这就是简单的练习过程
so that's a simple exercise.
如果你需要掌握如何在动画软件中画出运动效果
If you just need to to get used to how movement works in an animation program,
不要先画枪兵或是具体角色，而是先画点
don't do the Marine first,the character ,do the dot.
点动画能帮助你理解角色如何运动
The dot will help you understand how the motion works,
如何恰当地加速和减速
how to slow things down and speed things up properly,
我认为这是个很好的练习
and I think it's a good exercise,
这就是做动画最快的办法，也是个很好的小练习
so it is the quickest way to animates and a nice little exercise,
正如我所展示的
and it can be as I showed you,
一个适用于所有人物运动的教程
a guide for your motion for a character whatever it is,
好了 你现在已经学会了
OK, you figure it out.
点动画确实有用
But yeah, dots can help.
这就是全部内容了
So that's it guys.
为你们做的一个动画小教程
a little quick little animation tutorial for you.
展示了点动画和这个小练习
how dot animation or a quick little animation exercise can help you out.
希望你们喜欢这个视频
hope you enjoyed this video.
希望你能从这里学到东西
I hope you find it insightful
如果想让我做更多的动画教程
if you'd like me to do more animation tutorials.
请在评论中告诉我
let me know in the comments below,
让我知道你们想看的内容
and let me know what you would like to see,
不管是示例还是动画
whether it's you know, illustration, or animation, whatever it is.
或是教程、我们做视频的流程，总之我很乐意听到你们的声音
or tutorials and how we make videos, whatever they would be great to know.
感谢收看，希望你们喜欢这个视频
So thanks for watching guys hope you enjoyed it
周末还会出一期风暴英雄动画
and we're gonna see you his weekend because it's gonna be Heroes of the Storm episode and it can be a good way.
我相信你们会喜欢的
I think you guys are gonna like it
它也是这集教程的一个应用示例
It's a good little reference in this episode , this week's episode,
各位再见
Alright see you guys later,
享受夏季 拜拜
have fun enjoy the summer. Bye.